Okay, if you've got it, great job.
こうなっていれば 成功です
And if you didn't, good try and keep watching for the answer.
上手くいかなくても大丈夫 答えを見ていきましょう
All right, so here I am in Android Studio.
さて Android Studio にいます
And I'm looking at the TextViews right now.
今は テキストビューを見ています
But I'm going to scroll up to look at the ImageView.
スクロールして イメージビューを見ます
Okay, so a little bit about what I was talking about before.
前にお話ししましたが
If I put my cursor somewhere in this ImageView,
イメージビューにカーソルを置くと
it's going to give me a blue box that shows me how big the ImageView is.
イメージビューの大きさが 青いボックスで表示されます
And it's pretty much the entire size of this phone screen.
これはスマホ画面のサイズです
Now I'm going to go ahead and add scaleType, and
scaleType を加えますが
the two options that I'm looking at are center or centerCrop.
ここで探す２つのオプションは center か centorCrop です
Now center doesn't actually scale the image,
center は画像を実際に 拡大縮小するわけではなく
it doesn't change the size of the image.
画像のサイズは変えません
So it makes it a pretty straightforward that I need to use centerCrop.
ですから centerCrop を使います
Okay, and you should see that the image now expands to fill the entire
これで画像が イメージビューの空間全体に
ImageView space.
広がるはずです
You might notice here that at the bottom there's a little white
下の方に白い帯があって
strip where the image doesn't expand to.
全体には広がっていません
If I go up here, which let's me choose between different devices, and
ここで他のデバイスを選択したとすると
I choose say a tablet like a Nexus 10,
例えば Nexus 10 といった タブレットを選ぶと
we can see that this image is not filling the entire space.
画像は画面一杯に広がりません
Now this is bad because it means if you're viewing this on a tablet you're
これはマズイですね つまりタブレットで見ると
going to get this weird boxy image with this white space around it.
白い枠があるおかしな画像が 表示されるわけです
Although it might look fine on a phone.
スマホでは 大丈夫なんですけどね
The reasoning for
match_parent でなく
Let me change these to match_parent.
match_parent に変更しましょう
Now when I change these to match_parent the image expands to fill
match_parent に変更して
So the point I am trying to make is that layout_width, layout_height, and
layout_width と layout_height
scaleType all work together.
scaleType を一緒に機能します
Let me draw you a picture to show you a little more detail about what I mean.
これを図で説明しましょう
Okay, so let's say you are a bit curious about what's actually happening when we
centerCrop では 何が起こるのだろうと
use centerCrop.
関心があるでしょう
If you go to the Android Developers website,
Android Developers ウェブサイトに行くと
you will see that the documentation says the following.
次のように書かれています
centerCrop scales the image uniformly,
centerCrop は画像を 均一に拡大縮小します
meaning that it maintains the image's aspect ratio.
つまり 画像のアスペクト比を維持します
And what this means is that it does this so that both dimensions, the width and
ですから どちらの寸法 つまり 画像の幅も高さも
the height of the image will be equal to or
等しいままか 対応するイメージビューの―
larger than the corresponding dimension of the image view (minus padding).
寸法より大きくなります (パディングは引く）
Okay, so one thing I can say about scaling uniformly,
均一に拡大縮小する場合
if you've ever tried to scale an image, scaling uniformly means that it
画像を均一に拡大縮小するというのは
keeps the image from getting stretched out either horizontally or vertically.
画像を水平方向や 垂直方向に引き伸ばさないことです
So it does that scale, and then it makes the image large enough so
拡大縮小では 幅と高さを等しく
that both the width and height are going to be equal to or
画像を大きくするか
larger than the corresponding dimensions of the image itself.
画像の対応する寸法より 拡大します
Let's look at a picture.
つまり こういうことです
Okay, so here's your phone.
あなたのスマホがあります
And on our phone we have an image view.
私達のスマホには イメージビューがあります
Here's the picture for the image view, and
これがイメージビューのための写真で
here's the green box representing the actual size of the image view.
緑色のボックスは実際の イメージビューのサイズを表します
What's centerCrop will do, will scale this image up so
centerCrop で行うのは この画像をゆがめることなく
that without warping it, it fits in the box.
拡大縮小して ボックスに合わせます
Okay, so without changing the dimensions I've scaled this image up to make it fit
縮尺比に従って
in this green box here.
画像を緑色のボックスに合わせて 拡大します
Now because the image is this long rectangle,
この画像は長方形ですから
it actually expands over the edge of the phone.
スマホをはみ出してしまいます
centerCrop will center this image in the view, and
centerCrop でこの画像を 中央に置き
then as the name implies, it'll crop off the excess parts of the image.
その名前の通り画像の はみ出した部分を切り取ります
Okay, so I want to talk about one more problem that you might have run into.
もうひとつ解決してほしいことがあります
Views can overlap each other much like playing cards can overlap each other.
ビュー同士がトランプの様に 重なり合うことがありますね
And the order of these view tags here determines the order
ビュータグの順序で
that the views get placed on the screen.
画面に現れるビューの順序が決まります
So since view A is first,
ビュー A がまず
it would get placed on the screen first, followed by view B, and then view C.
画面に最初に現れ ビュー B ビュー C と続きます
Now because of the ordering that I put in this XML,
XML をこの順序にしているため
I can't really see my text very well in text view A.
テキストビュー A の テキストがよく見えません
Let's try changing the XML and see how it rearranges my screen.
XML を変更して 画面が どう変化するのか見てみましょう
Okay, so I've switched things around so now I have view B, A, C.
ビューは B A C の順に変更しました
This will then draw view B first.
ビュー B を最初に表示し
Then it will draw view A.
次にビュー A がきます
And finally it'll place view C.
そして最後は ビュー C です
I've just reordered the views.
これでビューを並べ替えました
Everything is placed in the same position,
配置された位置は同じですが
but the ordering of how the views stack on top of each other has changed.
ビューの重なり順が変わりました
And because of that, now I can see my text.
そのおかげでテキストが見えます
So you might have run into a similar problem with your card if
テキストビュー２つと 画像ビューが１つだと
you put your two text views here and then you drew your image view.
同じような問題が起きると思います
Because it would draw your first text view, then your second text view, and
それは まず最初のテキストビュー 次のテキストビュー
then the image, which takes up the whole screen, would have covered both of them.
そして 画面一杯に広がる画像がきて 両方のテキストを覆ってしまうのです
So just make sure that you got the ordering correct.
正しい順序になるよう気をつけましょう
Let's take a look at what that looks like in code.
コードではどうなっているでしょうか
Okay so here's my working code.
これが作業中のコードです
But I'm just going to show you what I mean by the ordering of views.
ビューの順序について説明します
Right now my ImageView is placed first, then my two TextViews.
まず イメージビューを設置し テキストビューが２つ置かれます
And we can see the text easily on the screen.
画面でテキストは簡単に見つけられます
Now if I instead, cut this ImageView, I'm going to scroll down,
代わりに イメージビューを切り取り 下にスクロールして
I'm going to past it right here.
ここに貼り付けます
All right, and now I have TextView, TextView, ImageView.
これで テキストビュー テキストビューとイメージビューです
Well, it draws the "Happy Birthday,
「 Happy Birthday Ben! 」 テキストビューをまず描きます
And then it draws this Android party image over the other two TextViews.
そして Android party の画像が 他のテキストビュー上に描きます
If I select the TextViews, I can see that they're still there,
ここで テキストビューを選択すると存在しますが
they're just being covered up by the ImageView.
イメージビューに覆われています
All right, I'm going to switch it back.
さて 元に戻しますよ
That's much better, my TextViews are on top now.
良くなりました テキストビューが上に来ます
Okay, and as we always do, let's go ahead and run this on our phone,
実際にスマホで実行して
just to make sure that everything is working with the match_parents and
match_parents と centerCrop が
the centerCrop.
機能しているかを確かめます
Okay, awesome, this is looking pretty great.
これはいいですね
We have our image expanded to fill the entire view, we can see our text views.
画像はビューいっぱいに広がり テキストビューも見えます
There's one tiny little problem that we still need to fix, but great job so far.
まだ少し修正するところがありますが 上手くいっています
All right, you're doing a great job. Only one more attribute to change,
よく頑張りましたね 属性をもうひとつ変更して
and then we're going to have our final birthday card.
バースデーカードを完成させましょう